The origin of this asymmetry occurs when you have the movement of the notochordal process.
It creates a node here called Hensen's node.
We find another image of this node, it's here, now it's located below.
We see another image, it's here now, you see it here.
This movement, what we call the rise in the formation of this
notochordal axis.
Do you remember?
If I now go inside...
What do I see? I see that within this structure, there are internal
micro-signs.
It is thanks to Kartagener's syndrome that Japanese researchers discovered the system.
They realized there was a disorder of laterality when people developed the heart on the right instead of the left.
They began to search for where they first found these small signs.
In life, in the body, there are many of these small signs.
The sperm.
These small cilia, in the uterus and the fallopian tubes there are these small cilia, in the
bronchi you have these small cilia, etc. And for the first time, they discovered, in
the part of Hensen's node, inside, they observed there were also small
cilia, but they did not perform a back-and-forth movement, but rather a
is the node
of Hensen moving, which is here, and right next to it are these small cilia.
And each time there are cells and then there's like a small snow of tissue we call
and at the moment when they
rotate they have an acceleration when they are away from the light of the lower part
it creates
a movement like this okay so this
concentrates these small molecules
to one side, which are pushed
to the left side
of the embryo. These small
vesicles burst
and release a new subtle snow
of pre-morphogenetic molecules,
which means you have
an internal asymmetry that will develop.
The heart will develop
more on the left, the liver, etc.
And it will develop this whole asymmetry.
In your body,
on the outside, you appear
rather symmetrical, but inside, you have a great asymmetry.
Be it in terms of brain function, ocular, etc., etc.,
throughout your body.
It’s an axis that connects your sacrum and the base of your skull.
It’s the flow of the asymmetry of your embryo.
So its organization of laterality.
You have a cascade of these small molecules
that will release proteins.
Specific ones we call Sonic Hedgehog, specific genes with zinc,
etc.,
which will activate on one side what we call the
caronty and hypercalcium system.
And this calcium activity is what intervenes in the development of
cells
for the faster development of one side compared to the other.